<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Matthew Lincoln</title>
		<description>Art History Ph.D student, University of Maryland</description>
		<link>http://matthewlincoln.net</link>
		<pubDate>2013-08-09T15:37:11-04:00</pubDate>
		<atom:link href="http://matthewlincoln.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Parsing the Smithsonian</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/08/scraping-the-smithsonian.html&quot;&gt;Yesterday I posted&lt;/a&gt; about a Ruby script I published for scraping information from &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.si.edu&quot;&gt;collections.si.edu&lt;/a&gt;. Today I &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdlincoln/si-scrape&quot;&gt;pushed a sister script , &lt;code&gt;si-parse.rb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, that will turn &lt;code&gt;si-scrape.rb&lt;/code&gt;’s raw HTML output into well-formed JSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d initially wanted to try and make this tool as friendly to tech-uncomfortable humanities scholars as possible, and have it spit out a CSV that could be opened and manipulated in Excel. However, to do that would not just mean flattening the Smithsonian data, but squashing it completely. Even a carefully-limited query on &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.si.edu&quot;&gt;collections.si.edu&lt;/a&gt; could return you a list containing paintings side by side with airplane models, oral history transcripts, articles of clothing, photographs, and library catalog records. A two-dimensional table would have hundreds of thousands of unused cells, as rows describing paintings would have to leave room for video duration tags, call numbers, or industrial manufacturer descriptions required by other objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than try to anticipate multiple cases of desired functionality, and thus potentially limit the tool’s &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; functionality, I elected to dump everything into the flexible &lt;a href=&quot;http://json.org&quot;&gt;JSON format&lt;/a&gt;, which can reliably describe objects with heterogeneous metadata, and comes standard with the ability to handle data fields with multiple values (such as a “topic” field with multiple assigned keywords). I’m already trying out all kinds of ways to search and interpret this data, and it works like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what average scholar in the humanities would know what to do with this output?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/computer.gif&quot; alt=&quot;computer confusion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was reminded of a minor debate that came up during a session from this June’s THATCamp Prime on scripting languages (&lt;a href=&quot;http://chnm2013.thatcamp.org/notepads/scripting-for-humanists/&quot;&gt;notes available here&lt;/a&gt;) proposed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://lincolnmullen.com/blog/report-from-thatcamp/&quot;&gt;Lincoln Mullen&lt;/a&gt;. There was some back and forth about whether or not the most tech-savy in the DH sphere ought to work harder to make easy to use interfaces for their tools, or whether it is instead better to ask scholars interested in digital approaches to roll up their sleeves and get (at least somewhat) familiar with computing details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first I felt the former attitude was the more productive one. If we are to spread digital humanities practices through the academy, shouldn’t we strive to make our tools as accessible as possible? Yet a counter-argument was raised that, just as many programs require their students gain competency in applicable foreign languages, shouldn’t it be acceptable to ask a budding digital humanist to learn applicable coding languages?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanities scholars are (rightly) fond of saying that they embrace complex arguments that can’t be boiled down to a bumper sticker or a bullet point. Perhaps they will increasingly come to embrace not only vital complexity in digital methodologies, but also their own capacity to learn these tools and bend them to their own needs. Some fantastic resources, like Jason Heppler’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://jasonheppler.org/rubyist-historian/&quot;&gt;Rubyist Historian&lt;/a&gt;, are already helping to bridge this knowledge gap. I anticipate (hope?) that as more and more DH projects filter into traditional venues like the MLA or CAA conferences, we will see not only a rise in &lt;em&gt;acceptance&lt;/em&gt; of these projects as legitimate academic production, but also a rise in the &lt;em&gt;literacies&lt;/em&gt; needed to both create and critique them.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 09:57:32 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/09/parsing-the-smithsonian.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/09/parsing-the-smithsonian.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Scraping the Smithsonian</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m proud to push one of my first real forays into digital humanities toolmaking to GitHub today: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdlincoln/si-scrape&quot;&gt;si-scrape&lt;/a&gt;, a Ruby script that scrapes data off of the Smithsonian Institution’s collection web portal &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.si.edu&quot;&gt;collections.si.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a quick and dirty implementation at the moment (one that will be happily outdated once the Smithsonian finishes deploying a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linked_data&quot;&gt;Linked Open Data&lt;/a&gt; interface!) but it could hopefully serve as a model for web-scraping other institutions whose public-facing collection websites are at least partially machine-readable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to run it is the URL that &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.si.edu&quot;&gt;collections.si.edu&lt;/a&gt; generates once you define a search query. For example, searching for objects of the type &lt;code&gt;Works of Art&lt;/code&gt; that feature the keyword &lt;code&gt;&quot;space&quot;&lt;/code&gt; generates this URL: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://collections.si.edu/search/results.htm?tag.cstype=all&amp;amp;q=space&amp;amp;fq=object_type:%22Works+of+art%22
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plug this URL into &lt;code&gt;si-scrape.rb&lt;/code&gt; and it will deliver a ~50 MB HTML file that concatenates all the returned records that &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.si.edu&quot;&gt;collections.si.edu&lt;/a&gt; normally paginates over hundreds of pages. You can then further parse this HTML to pull out the desired data. The Smithsonian has done rather well with this web interface; almost all of the metadata fields for a given object have been nicely tagged in the HTML so that you can easily have the computer hunt down &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;topic&lt;/code&gt; classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to make future versions of this script that will output a flat CSV that one can open and manipulate in Excel, making this script more accessible to the broader humanities community that doesn’t care to fumble with Ruby and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nokogiri.org&quot;&gt;Nokogiri&lt;/a&gt;. Such an implementation would need to be flexible enough to accept the huge range of metadata fields that the Smithsonian’s expansive and diverse collections demand. More experienced Ruby wranglers are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdlincoln/si-scrape&quot;&gt;welcome to contribute&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m already using this script to do some bulk processing of the keyword schemae in the Smithsonian art collections. In a future post I’ll be talking a bit more in depth about that, but for now here is a pretty teaser of a topic co-occurrence map of the Smithsonian American Art Museum’s painting collection, all of it collected using &lt;code&gt;si-scrape.rb&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images-display/saam_dated_full.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/saam_dated_full.png&quot;&gt;Download the full ~15MB image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. And yes, I got the idea for this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phdcomics.com/comics.php?f=1617&quot;&gt;while I was in the shower yesterday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 09:48:16 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/08/scraping-the-smithsonian.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/08/scraping-the-smithsonian.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>VerbalExpressions</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jehna/VerbalExpressions&quot;&gt;Jehna&lt;/a&gt; has come up with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeescript.org/&quot;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; of regular expressions: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jehna/VerbalExpressions&quot;&gt;VerbalExpressions&lt;/a&gt;, a JavaScript library (already implemented in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/VerbalExpressions&quot;&gt;host of other languages&lt;/a&gt;, including Ruby) that makes regex almost human-writeable. (tip: &lt;a href=&quot;http://thechangelog.com/stop-writing-regular-expressions-express-them-with-verbal-expressions/&quot;&gt;The Changelog&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kleinschmidt&quot;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is going to really ease parsing datasets with idiosyncratic conventions. See how the Ruby implementation works on the location headings in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getty.edu/research/tools/vocabularies/ulan/about.html&quot;&gt;ULAN&lt;/a&gt; that annoyingly concatenate unique id numbers with preferred terms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;verbal_expressions&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;location&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;5600392409/New York City (New York state, United States) (inhabited place)&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;num_query&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;VerEx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;start_of_line&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;anything_but&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;num_query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# =&amp;gt; ^(?:[^/]*)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;content_query&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;VerEx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;find&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;anything_but&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;(&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;content_query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# =&amp;gt; (?:/)(?:[^\(]*)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;slice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;num_query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# =&amp;gt; 5600392409&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;slice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;content_query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# =&amp;gt; New York City&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 05:41:21 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/06/verbalexpressions.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/06/verbalexpressions.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Presenting at the Sixteenth Century Society Conference</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will be presenting this paper at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sixteenthcentury.org/conference/&quot;&gt;Sixteenth Century Society Conference&lt;/a&gt; in San Juan on October 24, 2013:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;occult-text-and-image-in-georg-bocskays-and-joris-hoefnagels-mira-calligraphiae-monumenta&quot;&gt;Occult Text and Image in Georg Bocskay’s and Joris Hoefnagel’s &lt;em&gt;Mira calligraphiae monumenta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getty.edu/art/gettyguide/artObjectDetails?artobj=2648&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.getty.edu/art/collections/images/l/00264801.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mira calligraphiae monumenta fol. 83. Pomegranate, Worm, and Peach, from the &amp;quot;Mira calligraphiae monumenta&amp;quot; by Joris Hoefnagel, illuminator; and Georg Bocskay, scribe. Illumination 1591-1596, script 1561-1562. The J. Paul Getty Museum, MS. 20, FOL. 83. Image © 2013, The J. Paul Getty Trust. All rights reserved.&quot; title=&quot;Mira calligraphiae monumenta fol. 83. Pomegranate, Worm, and Peach, from the *Mira calligraphiae monumenta* by Joris Hoefnagel, illuminator; and Georg Bocskay, scribe. Illumination 1591-1596, script 1561-1562. The J. Paul Getty Museum, MS. 20, FOL. 83. Image © 2013, The J. Paul Getty Trust. All rights reserved.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Mira calligraphiae monumenta&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most intriguing objects of the &lt;em&gt;kusntkammer&lt;/em&gt; of Rudolf II. The creators of this layered work never met each other; Georg Bocskay, secretary for Ferdinand I, penned the manuscript’s calligraphic displays in 1561-2, while Joris Hoefnagel was commissioned by Rudolf three decades later to illuminate this treasure with brilliantly rendered flora and fauna. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been argued that Hoefnagel’s additions establish a &lt;em&gt;paragone&lt;/em&gt; between the painted image and the written word, his illusionistic &lt;em&gt;naturalia&lt;/em&gt; surpassing Bocskay’s page-bound &lt;em&gt;artificialia&lt;/em&gt;. It has been further argued that the outcome of this &lt;em&gt;paragone&lt;/em&gt; reflects a Paracelsian philosophy shared by the Rudolfine court: that true knowledge can only come from natural investigation and not from secondary texts. However, this interpretation elides the complexities of magical and occult studies in Prague. The diverse schools of occult thought entertained at the Rudolfine court also included that of Heinrich Cornelius Agrippa, who believed inscribed signs had the capacity to become sigils endowed with power over the natural world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I argue that the complex formal interplay of text and image on certain pages of the &lt;em&gt;MCM&lt;/em&gt; at times suggests that Bocskay’s scripts indeed hold sway over Hoefnagel’s natural objects. This suggests that even as Rudolf and his court appreciated the &lt;em&gt;MCM&lt;/em&gt; for its aesthetic beauty and inventiveness, these semiotically-intelligent readers must also have related its formally-cohesive tableaus of text and nature to sixteenth-century occult notions of the physical power of the inscribed sign investigated in their own court.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 06:44:41 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/05/presenting-at-the-sixteenth-century-society-conference.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/05/presenting-at-the-sixteenth-century-society-conference.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Humanities in Crisis... since the Renaissance?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew Keener &lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewkeener.wordpress.com/2013/07/31/jacob-burckhardt-and-the-crisis-in-renaissance-humanities/&quot;&gt;smartly notes&lt;/a&gt; that Jacob Burckhardt described a kind of “crisis in the humanities” that took place in the sixteenth century. In Burckhardt’s 1860 &lt;em&gt;Die Kultur der Renaissance in Italien&lt;/em&gt;, we read about the rise of scholarly acrimony:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Of all men who ever formed a class, they had the last sense of their common interests…. All means were held lawful, if one of them saw a change of supplanting another. From literary discussion they passed with astonishing suddenness to the fiercest and most groundless vituperation. Not satisfied with refuting, they sought to annihilate an opponent. (272-73)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keener sees parallels to the current humanities crisis rhetoric:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I want to emphasize that Burckhardt’s account, composed during the mid-nineteenth century, delivers a picture of sixteenth-century Europe in which the humanist struggled to get by. The wide availability of printed books rendered his lectures and expertise less relevant or necessary. He faced opposition from the public, and was scorned as self-indulgent, extravagant, and atheistic. However, he also attacked and was attacked by other humanists in a heated race for influence and glory. Wandering up and down the country in search of stable income, the humanist ultimately found it difficult to settle in one place, and found himself disconnected from the public, which “demanded something new.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 04:44:07 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/01/humanities-in-crisis-since-the-renaissance.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/08/01/humanities-in-crisis-since-the-renaissance.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A life in an infographic</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Something interesting that cropped up while I was on vacation last week. The design agency &lt;a href=&quot;http://accurat.it&quot;&gt;Accurat&lt;/a&gt; (which has developed several other novel visualizations of cultural texts and histories) has created intriguing infographics &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/accurat/sets/72157633953437972/with/8961090343/&quot;&gt;visualizing ten modern painters’ lives&lt;/a&gt;. (hat tip: &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyperallergic.com/76259/10-painters-lives-chronicled-as-infographics/&quot;&gt;hyperallergic&lt;/a&gt; via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MSCollaboratory/status/360456068507250688&quot;&gt;MSCVC&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/accurat/8961090259/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3806/8961090259_ba40cf018d_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visualising Painters&#39; Lives by accurat.it, on Flickr&quot; title=&quot;Visualising Painters&#39; Lives by accurat.it, on Flickr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have structured the infographics as multi-layered timelines marked with single-point events, spans of time indicating things such as a career in a studio or academy, or a romantic or professional relationship. Affixed to these representations of the artist’s life are timelines of their work signposted with landmark paintings, sigils rendered in the color schemes observed at that phase in the painter’s career, and histograms that claim to mark out that artist’s participation in a certain artistic school or movement. The iconography is delightfully idiosyncratic, shaped to resemble motifs that have come to be associated with each of the ten artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/matisselegend.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/matisselegend.png&quot; alt=&quot;Detail from Henri Matisse&quot; title=&quot;Detail of the histogram legend from the Matisse infographic. By accurat.it&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m particularly interested in the histograms charting artwork style, size, and palette. Accurat did a particularly admirable job visualizing the many schools and movements interweaved through each artist’s oeuvre: color-coded words are clustered and stacked near concentrations of paintings that exhibit a certain style, e.g. expressionism or cubism. But because bars on the histogram are keyed to these colors, it is also possible to clearly indicate one instance of late cubism in Matisse’s oeuvre, while still legibly showing that most of his experimentation with that style happened earlier in his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some errant thoughts on the project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While Accurat points out these graphs are by no means comprehensive or “scientific”, they mention that they drew data from open online databases like Wikipedia, so I wonder to what extent they automated this process.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Could one do something similar with data culled from &lt;a href=&quot;http://artstor.org&quot;&gt;ARTstor&lt;/a&gt;, which has very solid date and repository information, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://artsy.net/&quot;&gt;artsy&lt;/a&gt;, which has tagged a wealth of works with more squishy metadata like color and movement?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A histogram of different styles works quite well for the exhaustively-taxonimized twentieth century, but I suspect this might not be quite as illuminating for earlier periods that haven’t been dissected into named stylistic movements. Maybe it would be productive to make a histogram of genres (portraits, landscapes, altarpieces) or sizes and compositional schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 06:09:26 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/31/a-life-in-an-infographic.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/31/a-life-in-an-infographic.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Race Point, Provincetown, MA</title>
				<description>&lt;!-- Photo sphere JS --&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;https://apis.google.com/js/plusone.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;g:panoembed imageurl=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-rBS1zG2wpgY/UfiSmxk9c3I/AAAAAAAAAkk/9sLOd618_DY/w1594-h797-no/&quot; fullsize=&quot;4000,2000&quot; croppedsize=&quot;4000,2000&quot; offset=&quot;0,0&quot; displaysize=&quot;600,400&quot; /&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 03:39:40 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/31/race-point-provincetown.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/31/race-point-provincetown.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Augustine's City of God</title>
				<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Man, by worshiping the works of his own hands, may more easily cease to be man, than the works of his hands can, through his worship of them, become gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustine, &lt;em&gt;City of God&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 07:39:28 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/24/augustine%27s-city-of-god.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/24/augustine%27s-city-of-god.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Academia's four letter word</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been some hubub over the weekend about San Jose State University &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/blogs/future_tense/2013/07/19/san_jose_state_suspends_udacity_online_classes_after_students_fail_final.html&quot;&gt;dropping its partnership with Udacity&lt;/a&gt;, an online-learning startup, because of an abysmal failure rate running from 56 to 76 percent over five different massive open online courses. A Chronicle blogger &lt;a href=&quot;http://chronicle.com/blognetwork/tenuredradical/2013/07/f-is-for-failure-or-dont-invest-your-pension-in-moocs-yet/&quot;&gt;offers a good read&lt;/a&gt; on the underlying problems of MOOC trials at SJSU, although others suggest that Udacity’s bust &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Elijah_Meeks/status/359090677654630401&quot;&gt;should be thought of as online education’s “Pets.com”&lt;/a&gt;, an early failure of paradigm-shifting online retail. And some &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jtheibault/status/357604686162968576&quot;&gt;just don’t want to talk about the M-word at all&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve little to add to the larger debate over the place of MOOCs in the future of higher ed writ large. From my own small corner though, I’m interested if open courses could be useful to graduate students who find themselves needing to supplement their program’s coursework with ancillary technical or administrative skills, like scripting languages or grant writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could the current surplus of technical MOOCs be especially useful for budding digital humanities scholars? In the spirit of trying it before I knock it, I’ve enrolled in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/sna&quot;&gt;MOOC on social network analysis&lt;/a&gt; for this fall, and a faculty colleague will be working through one on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/maps&quot;&gt;GIS&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll find out soon enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 06:05:04 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/22/academias-four-letter-word.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/22/academias-four-letter-word.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Big Humanities</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ischool.drexel.edu/bigdata/bigdata2013/&quot;&gt;IEEE BigData 2013&lt;/a&gt; is going to be accompanied this year by a two-day workshop on “big data” applications in the humanities. Some promising-sounding &lt;a href=&quot;http://bighumanities.net/&quot;&gt;topics from their CFP&lt;/a&gt; include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Text- and data-mining of historical and archival material.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Social media analysis, including sentiment analysis&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cultural analytics&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Crowd-sourcing and big data&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cyber-infrastructures for the humanities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Relationship between “small data” and big data&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;NoSQL databases and their application, e.g. document and graph databases&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Big data and the construction of memory and identity&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Big data and archival practice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Construction of big data&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Big data in Heritage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will be accepting long and short paper proposals until August 5.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 06:04:30 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/21/big-humanities.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://matthewlincoln.net/2013/07/21/big-humanities.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>